Exceptions are just regular classes that inherit from the exception class.
And so I can ask, is subclass value error exception?
That's true, right?
And you can do this for all of the exceptions that we've been looking at.
So in order to make our own custom exceptions, all we need to do is subclass from exception,
just like all these other types of exceptions do.
So I can say class my custom exception, subclass from exception.
And then I can, it's not really matter.
You can even have just past which means it's, you know,
it's a valid statement in Python.
So it means you can kind of have an empty class without any variables or an initializer or anything like that.
Now I can raise this custom exception class by using the raised keyword.
Sorry, no colon there.
And now we get a trace back.
Going back to my custom exception.
This is a really useful way of signaling error conditions in your production Python code.
It's good to have custom exception classes so that you can then handle them as specifically as you want in your error checking code.
Does that make sense why?
Okay.
The nice thing about these custom exception classes is they don't have to get simple.
We can get this fancy as we want here.
So I'm going to make a new class the incorrect value error.
It's going to subclass from exception.
And I'm going to make a constructor here.
I'm going to take self.
And I'm also going to take value.
Now I know that exceptions all have a message.
I did that by looking at the documentation and you can't do.
But you know, bear with me for now.
I can say that for my error class.
I want the message to be got a bad value.
I'm going to actually print out what the value was.
How do I call the exception class and pass in my new message?
Super.
It's super.
Done.
Yep.
Then I pass in my new message.
So now I can say my value equals, you know.
And that if my value is greater than 998.
Oops.
I'm going to fix that underscore there.
If my value is greater than 998, raise my incorrect value error and pass in my value.
There we go.
It's my error message, right?
It looks like the other Python tracebacks.
It gives us the type and then it gives us the message.
So very useful, especially for logging.
We can do that this because exception in general takes a message.
So if I wanted to, and you know, don't do this.
Not good practice just showing you.
You generally don't want to raise exception because your custom error handling code, you know.
Probably doesn't do a good job of figuring out why this exception was thrown.
But you can pass in a message here and say whatever.
Whatever a message I want.
There we go.
Let's write a custom exception for our GitHub API.